ADEDEJI STEPHEN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, Oyo, Nigeria

https://adedejistephen.com . https://github.com/ionware . (234)-803-233-6192

PROFILE

Fullstack Engineer with 4+ years of demonstrated working experience at building small-scale to medium-scale web applications. I am passionate about building API that conforms to standards. I advocate for clean code and architecture. I am actively seeking more knowledge – if I do not know it, I will learn it.

EDUCATION

Kwara State Univeristy, Malete

AUG 2017 - SEPT 2021

BSc Computer Science

Relevant courses: Data Structure and Algorithm, Principe of programming with **C** and **Java**, Database design, CS50 Harvard Uni

Technical skills: Javascript(4yrs), PHP(5yrs), SQL, Git, Cloud computing

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Developer Students Clubs, Google Developers

Aug, 2019 - Jul, 2020

Club Lead

Grew club members from 20 to about 100+ members through awareness, campus-wide publicity, and tech orientation programs.

Collaborated with the National Association of computer science students to plan, and hold the first-ever Hackathon in the university.

Held three months of intensive programming Bootcamp in the field of UI/UX, web development, and mobile app development for about 120+ students.

Developer Students Clubs, Google Developers

Jul, 2018 - Jul, 2019

Core-team, Web track Lead

Led the web development group of 8+ students to build websites for local businesses with the university community.

Taught the fundamentals of web dev in club Bootcamp and weekly held workshops.

Taught the fundamentals of React library to intermediate developers in the club.

Held workshops to introduce members to server-side programming using ${\bf NodeJS}$ with ${\bf Express.}$

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Javascript/ECMAScript, PHP, SQL

Web Technology

Rest, HTML5, CSS, SASS, PWA

Web Frameworks / Library

Laravel, React, Sails.js

Database & tools

JSON, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis

EXPERIENCES

Haqqman, Abuja, NG

Feb 2020 - Mar 2021

Fullstack Web Developer

Designed and documented **API** for a new product from scratch using **NodeJS**, and **Express**

Developed reusable UI components for user-facing web solution using React

Optimized backend services by suggesting and implementing a dynamic database that accommodates our data structure.

Deployed and managed **MERN** app on cloud service using **Nginx** server running on **CentOS**

Improved UI components on a multi-vendor e-commerce web application

Reduced spam rate using Akismet with Google ReCaptcha, saving 80%+ of mail service quota

Developed Web infrastructure that delivers all company's project contact form submission to the right delegates using **Laravel**.

Timesystems, Lagos NG

Aug 2018 - Apr 2019

Fullstack Web Developer

Designed and developed an e-commerce web application for book vendors using PHP/Laravel, and MySQL database

Digitalized the activities of a multi-level organization by building robust web solution using **React**, and **PHP/Laravel**

Built a multi-channel web system for reporting cases of gender-based violence

Implemented Geolocation and Geoencoding feature to improve search in a job search application by leveraging on Google API services

Hotels.ng, Lagos NG

Mar 2018 - Jul 2018

Software Engineering Intern

Improved users' UI module by implementing UI mockup using $\mathbf{HTML}/\mathbf{SASS}$

Implemented room reservations service for customers by integrating backend service into Hotels API services

Optimized the response time of the API by replacing legacy composer modules

Reviewed, and iterate pull-requests of other team members on **GitHub**